ANDREW ORFALEA

(805) – 570 - 4449 aorfalea@gmail.com Santa Barbara, CA

https://www.linkedin.com/in/andy-orfalea/

Motivated and resourceful data scientist with over 10 years of upper management business administration experience. Adaptable, quick learner and always eager for the next challenge. At my core, I'm a people person. Well versed in performing under pressure through collaborative and communicative team dynamics.

SKILLS

- Business Strategy,
- Operations Management
- Python
- Git/GitHub
- Machine Learning and Deep Learning
- Tableau
- Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

General Assembly | Data Science Immersive

January 2022 - April 2022

- Full time immersive program which included training in Python, Supervised and Unsupervised Machine Learning, and Data Visualization.
- Portfolio: https://aothree.github.io/

Freebirds Goleta, CA

General Manager

August 2011 - January 2022

- Analysis of financial statements and adjusting business strategy accordingly. Any recommendations to the owner had to be justified by statistical analysis.
- Accounts Payable. Ensuring 30+ vendors were paid in a timely manner.
- Administered and processed payroll, requiring accuracy of record keeping and timeliness to ensure compliance with all applicable state and federal laws.
- Managing 60+ employees including development, discipline and termination.
- Recruiting and Hiring. Interviewing, onboarding and training.
- Food quality. Responsible for upholding the restaurant's extremely high standards for freshness and flavor.
 Developed systems to numerically evaluate and record the quality of our ingredients.

Assistant Manager

June 2008 - August 2011

- Projecting hourly sales, for every hour of operation, based on detailed analysis of historical sales data & trends. Based on these projections, scheduling and adjusting labor.

- Scheduling for 60+ coworkers
- Creating and re-formatting forms to analyze data using Microsoft Excel and Google Sheets.
- Maintaining and troubleshooting issues for computers, points of sale and surveillance systems.

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Data Science Immersive

remote January 2022 - April 2022

Boston College Bachelor of Arts, English Boston, Massachusetts September 2004 – May 2008